原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译：草草 Alex Lynn_宁  杨一勾 C_C
翻译：木浅  辰星晓Reginamoon   校对：木浅  某羽
时间轴：念念 烟幕迟迟 Toozii
后期：斯人      总监：木浅
诉 讼 双 雄
第七季   第六集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
你人在这里  就得工作  不允许想家
When you work here, you don't think about home
-想亲人想孩子  -这不公平
- and families and babies. - That's not fair.
他不可能提前一年知道要生孩子...
He couldn't have known he was gonna have a baby a year--
我告诉你  斯蒂芬妮
Let me tell you something, Stephanie.
也许你不清楚生孩子的事
Maybe you don't know how babies are made,
因为想要孩子的人  就知道自己在尝试
because when people are trying, they know they're trying!
就因为没人愿意和你尝试
And just because no one ever wants to try with you
不代表你就有权
doesn't give you the right
教我怎么管理新律师
to tell me how to run my associates!
他们提出的是我这辈子都拿不到的钱
I got an offer for more money than I'll see my whole life,
结果你却想让我拒绝就因为你感觉
and you want me to turn it down based on a feeling
发生在克里斯身上的事也发生在了别人身上
that whatever happened to Chris happened to other people?
你在和自己的心理医生约会
You're dating your therapist.
我不需要你对我说教  路易
I don't need a lecture from you, Louis.
唐娜知道你俩的事吗
Does Donna have any idea about the two of you?
她不知道
No, she doesn't,
目前我想保持这种状态
and for right now, I'd like to keep it that way.
你还瞒着我什么  哈维
Harvey, is there something that you're not telling me?
最近觉得你变了个人
'Cause it seems like you've been different lately.
我们赢了  你就是躺在墨西哥沙滩上的
We win this, you're gonna be Andy Dufresne
安迪・杜佛兰
sitting on a beach in Mexico
带着一个满满的钱包
with a bank account full of cash.
我在这里本来过的就不错
I already make a nice living in here.
但我觉得这笔钱的一部分
I was thinking maybe some of that money
可以给你女儿
might go to your daughter.
我确实是在跟奥利佛办案
I wasn't lying about working a case with Oliver.
我只是没告诉你是哪件
I just didn't tell you which one.
-监狱案  -是的
- The prison one? - Yeah.
-这是要被辞退的  -哈维不会就为这解雇...
- This is a fireable offense. - Harvey isn't gonna fire me.
-但也许他应该  -你怎么这么说
- Yeah, but maybe he should. What is your word worth?
就目前的看来  它已经快要一文不值了
The way things are going, it's not gonna be worth very much.
你起来多久了
How long have you been up?
有一阵了
A while.
我一直在想你昨晚对我说的话
I've been thinking about what you said to me last night.
迈克  我没想说得那么过分的
Mike, I didn't mean to be so harsh.
不  你说得对
No, you were right.
我的承诺对我的确非常重要
My word does mean everything to me...
所以我要继续帮助奥利弗
which is why I'm gonna keep helping Oliver.
什么
What?
我向哈维做保证时  我是真心的
When I gave my word to Harvey, I meant it.
但之前  我也向奥斯卡・雷耶斯做了保证
But before that, I gave my word to Oscar Reyes.
对不起  但我现在不能退出
And I'm sorry, but I-I can't back out now.
好吧
Okay.
那么你又要在秘密中生活了
So you're just gonna live your life keeping secrets again?
-不是像那样的  -怎么不像了
- This isn't like that. - How is it not like that?
你在瞒着哈维
You're keeping this from Harvey.
哈维也瞒过杰西卡一些事
And Harvey kept things from Jessica.
结果如何呢
Look at how that turned out.
我现在告诉哈维  就跟他抓到我一样
I tell Harvey now, and it's the same as if he catches me.
案子被驳回  所有我们想帮助的人
The case gets tossed, and all of the people
会继续遭到不公对待
we're trying to help keep getting abused.
跟之前一样
It's the same as before.
不  瑞秋  这跟我是个骗子时不一样
No, Rachel, this is not the same as when I was a fraud.
我还告诉你
And I'll tell you something else--
我以前晚上会睡不着
I used to have trouble sleeping at night,
但我现在睡得很香
but I sleep like a baby now
因为我在帮助他们
because I am helping these people.
对不起  但我要遵守这个承诺
I'm sorry, but that's the word that I'm keeping.
早上好
Good morning.
你睡得好吗
Did you sleep well?
如果八小时的安眠算睡得好
If you consider eight hours of bliss sleeping well,
那么是的  我睡得很好
then, yes, I slept very well.
但现在  我得走了
But now I have to go.
-等等  -哈维  我还要见病人
- Wait. - Harvey, I have patients.
我知道  但我听听你的意见
I know, but I wanted to get your opinion on something.
你又做什么了
What have you done this time?
我还没告诉唐娜我们在约会
I haven't told Donna we're seeing each other yet.
为什么不
Why not?
拜托  你知道我跟她的历史
Come on, you know my history with her.
我们一起工作  我刚提拔了她
We're working together. I just promoted her.
这更多是借口不是理由  不是吗
That's more an excuse than a reason, isn't it?
我不想在没有问题时制造问题
I don't want to create a problem when there isn't one.
谁说非得有问题了
And who says there has to be one?
不非得有  但是...
There doesn't have to be one, but--
哈维  首先  你可能低估了她
Harvey, first of all, you may be underestimating her.
-唐娜已经是个大姑娘了  -宝拉...
- I mean, Donna's a big girl. - Paula--
其次  如果我错了
And second of all, if I'm wrong
你没低估她
and you're not underestimating her,
那等她回头自己发现
then you're only gonna cause both of you
事情只会更糟
a lot more trouble down the road when she finds out.
因为  哈维  她肯定会发现的
'Cause, Harvey, she is gonna find out.
所以你是让我告诉她
So you're telling me to tell her?
你已经知道你需要做什么了
You already know what you need to do.
你问我  是因为有时
You just asked me because sometimes
我们得听别人说出来
we need to hear it from someone else.
他们没说你还带了助手来
They didn't tell me you brought a sidekick.
弗兰克  这是奥利佛・格雷迪
Frank, this is Oliver Grady.
他是庭审律师
He's the one that's trying the case.
真厉害
Good for him.
我还是不明白你回来做什么
I still don't know what you're doing back here.
我知道的都告诉你了
I already told you everything I know.
不是一切  你该把消息源告诉我们了
Not everything. It's time you gave us the name of your source.
交易是  钱汇入我女儿的账户
The deal is that money goes into my daughter's account,
然后告诉你们名字
then you get the name.
-这是什么  -定金
- What the hell is this? - It's a down payment.
定金  不行
Down payment? I don't think so.
-我要全款  -如果你以为
- I want the whole thing. - And if you think
我们没拿到名字就会给你50万
we're giving you half a million without a name,
那你是疯了
then you're out of your mind.
那我们就陷入了所谓的僵局
Then we are at what they call an impasse,
因为没有钱  我不会告诉你名字
because I'm not giving you that name without that money.
如果案子被法官驳回
And there isn't gonna be any money
就不会有钱了
if the judge dismisses this case.
他在说什么
What the hell is he talking about?
他在说另一边提出动议
He's talking about the fact that the other side
撤销案件
filed a motion to dismiss this thing.
明天上庭
Goes to court tomorrow.
如果你不把消息源告诉我
If you don't give me the name of your source,
案子就要完了
it's gonna get tossed.
扯淡  才不会
Bullshit it's gonna get tossed.
我都承认我参与了
I already admitted to you I took part in it.
不够
It's not enough.
为什么不够  有我的证言
Why is that not enough? You got my word.
我们不能证实你的证言
We got no corroboration of your word.
谁知道不是我来找你时
What's to say you didn't make up this whole thing
你临时编的
when I came in here?
那去找我七年前找过的
Then go to the goddamn prosecutor
那个检察官
I went to seven years ago.
她都记录下来了
She's got it all on record.
她不是没往下查吗
I thought she didn't pursue this case.
那你听错了
Then you didn't hear me right.
她查了  但是没有做到底
She pursued it. She just didn't want to see it through.
去问她我说的是不是真的
Ask her if I'm telling the truth.
现在  留着你们的零钱吧
In the meantime, keep your pocket change,
因为我什么都不会说的
'cause you're not getting shit from me.
*看到钱  就愿意留下吃饭*
*See the money, wanna stay for your meal*
*给你太太再拿块馅饼*
*Get another piece of pie for your wife*
*所有人都想知道那感觉*
*Everybody wanna know how it feel*
*所有人都想见见那景象*
*Everybody wanna see what it's like*
*豆子馅饼我也愿吃  我不在乎*
*I'll even eat a bean pie, I don't mind*
*我和妹子忙着赚钱*
*Me and Missy is so busy, busy making money*
*好了*
*All right*
*退开点  我要跳舞*
*All step back, I'm 'bout to dance*
*美钞爵士摇摇摇*
*The greenback boogie*
诉讼双雄 第七季 第六集
伙计
Hey, buddy.
路易  我只是在泡咖啡
Louis, I was just making a cup of coffee.
我不是在休息  我发誓
I'm not taking any time off, I swear.
布莱恩  偶尔休息一下没什么不好
Whoa, Brian, it's okay to take a break every now and then.
-是吗  -当然了
- It is? - Yeah, absolutely.
事实上  咖啡准备非常重要
In fact, coffee preparation is very important.
是啊  其实泡咖啡是我最喜欢的事...
Yeah. Actually, making coffee is one of my favorite hobb--
太好了  听我说  我有事要问你
That's great. Listen to me, I need to ask you something.
那天  我对你说那些话时
The other day when I said those things to you
关于休假的事
about taking time off, I mean,
我不记得你是不是还记得
I don't even know if you remember it.
历历在目
Like it was yesterday.
那样的话  我想问
Well, in that case I was just wondering...
我当时多过分
how bad was I?
也不是那么糟糕啦
You weren't that bad.
很好
Good.
你愿意在法庭上这么说吗
Now, would you be willing to swear to that in court?
-什么  为什么  -没为什么
- What? Why? - No reason.
事实上  我对当时的印象和你的一样
Truth is, my recollection is exactly the same as yours.
你想休几天假  我批准了
You asked for a couple days off, and I gave it to you.
瞧  我甚至把它写在了日记里
See, I even wrote it in my diary.
"给布莱恩放了两天假  感觉棒极了"
"Gave Brian two days off. Felt good about it."
这看上去像是今天写的
It looks like you just wrote that today.
-为什么这么说  -顶上的日期是今天
- What makes you say that? - It has today's date on top.
我今天刚写下来是为了记住今天的谈话
I just wrote that down to remember today's conversation.
我能回去工作了吗
Can I go back to work now?
去吧  尽快把你的书面证词放我桌上
Yep, just make sure you have the affidavit on my desk as soon as possible.
谢谢你这么快就见我们  兰道夫女士
Thanks for seeing us on such short notice, Ms. Randolph.
不得不承认  弗兰克・加洛这个名字
I have to say, when I heard the name Frank Gallo,
勾起了我的兴趣
my interest was piqued.
有什么事
What's this about?
我们是一群囚犯起诉
We're representing a class of prisoners
改造公司虐囚的诉讼代理人
suing Reform Corporation for abusive practices.
我们来这里是为了证实
We're here to confirm that
弗兰克・加洛七年前来见过你
Frank Gallo came to see you seven years ago
并且承认自己卷入了一起阴谋
and admitted to being involved in a conspiracy.
没错  他来找我  自荐为线人
Yeah, he came to me offering to be an informant
想以此换取保护
in exchange for protection
不被兰伯特里发生的事殃及
from what was going on in Lambert.
你相信他告诉你的事吗
And did you believe what he told you?
我当然相信  他被打了
Of course I believed him. He was beaten up,
在医务室里整整待了两周
and he'd been in the infirmary for two goddamn weeks.
如果你真相信他
Well, if you believed him,
为什么不追查这个案子
why the hell didn't you pursue the case?
我查了  我把它捅到了最上面
I did pursue it. I ran it up the flagpole,
但最终却重重地砸回了我身上
and it came back down like a concrete block.
没人在乎那些囚犯和他们的遭遇
No one gives a shit about prisoners or the way they're treated.
所以他另外提出告他狱友的密
So, instead, he offered to inform on his fellow inmates,
然后借此机会转狱
and then he used that to get himself transferred.
没错  好了  你们不介意的话
Exactly. Now, if you don't mind.
丹妮尔  我介意
Well, Danielle, in fact, I do mind.
我就是在乎这些囚犯的遭遇的一个
You see, I do give a shit about how prisoners are treated,
所以你得在庭上把你刚刚和我们说的话
which means you are gonna tell the court
一字不差地重复一遍
exactly what you just told us.
你是没听见我刚刚说的吗
Did you not hear what I just said?
这事最后砸回了我身上
It came back down on me like a concrete block.
这是我的事业  我...
This is my career. I--
我是不会公开作证危及我的事业的
I am not gonna go on record and jeopardize it.
你只能在两种里面选一个
Well, then this is gonna go one of two ways.
你把证据给我们
You give us your records,
我们默默地把它提交上去...
and we submit them quietly...
或者是我们依照信息自由法传唤你的证据
Or we subpoena your records under the Freedom of Information Act
再让你出庭作证
and put you on the stand.
既然你害怕危及自己的事业
And seeing as you're afraid of ruining your career,
我建议你选第一个
I suggest you go with option A.
你们两个小混蛋
You're a couple of little shits.
很好  你在这
Good, you're here.
听着  我一直想告诉你一些事
Listen, there's something I've been wanting to talk to you about.
哈维  你得等等再说了
Harvey, it's gonna have to wait.
唐娜  这事很重要
Donna, it's important.
弗兰克・加洛几分钟前给你留了留言
Frank Gallo left a message for you a few minutes ago.
-他说什么了  -他说你和迈克
- What did he say? - He said you and Mike
最后别想着再坑他一遍
better not be trying to screw him over again,
不然你们会后悔的
or you're gonna regret it.
哈维  他说这话是什么意思
Harvey, what's he talking about?
我不知道  但我现在就去弄清楚
I don't know, but I'm sure as hell gonna find out.
你怎么又和弗兰克・加洛搅在了一起
What the hell are you doing with Frank Gallo?
-哈维...  -别装傻
- Harvey-- - Don't pretend like you don't know.
他刚给我留了言
He just left me a message
让我确保你不会坑他
asking me to make sure that you don't fuck him over.
我告诉过你了
I told you,
我在处理布鲁克林房屋委员会的案子
I'm working on a Brooklyn Housing Authority case.
加洛来自布鲁克林  他认识人
Gallo is from Brooklyn. He knows people.
别告诉我他要你花钱买他的消息
And don't tell me he's making you pay for his information.
没错  而且我准备给他钱了
Yes, he is, and I'm gonna pay him.
迈克  他很可能屁都不知道
Mike, odds are he doesn't know jack shit
只是想利用你捞一笔
and he's just using you to get money.
不  我查过了的  好吗
No, I looked into it, all right?
他告诉我的信息都是真的
What he told me checks out.
这件事上他能帮上忙
He's on the right side of this thing.
你是想告诉我他忽然就变成大善人了吗
You're telling me he's all of a sudden Mother Teresa?
这家伙曾经想杀你
This guy tried to kill you!
我知道  听着  我没说他是个好人
I know that. Look, I'm not saying he's a saint.
我只是说我知道自己在干什么
I'm saying that I know what I'm doing.
你怎么就不明白呢
Don't you get it?
像加洛这样的人一定会复仇
A guy like Gallo finds people to get revenge on.
他会一直想  一直想
He thinks about it and thinks about it,
要想不被他报复
and the only way to survive that
唯有别被他想起来  让他去注意别人
is to stay out of his mind and let him find someone else.
也许你是对的
Maybe you're right,
但我已经向他保证
but I already promised him
用一些东西换取他的信息了
something for his information,
假如我现在反悔
and if I back out of that now,
我一定会成为他报复名单上的第一人
I'm gonna end up on the top of his list.
瑞秋知道这事吗
Does Rachel know about this?
-不知道  -那你最好祈祷
- No. - Then you better hope
加洛不会像给我留言这样
Gallo doesn't leave her a message
也去给她留言
the same way he left me one.
盯着窗外发呆呢  路易
Staring out the window, Louis?
这意味着出事了
That's a sign that something's going on.
没出什么事  瑞秋
Nothing's going on, Rachel.
那你到底为什么要逼着布莱恩・阿特曼
Then why exactly did you make Brian Altman
回忆那可怕的一天
relive that horrible day?
什么可怕的一天
Which horrible day?
就是你发疯  然后狠狠地
The one where you treated him like shit
羞辱了他的那天
because you were losing your mind.
那天
That day.
你想知道出什么事了是吧
You want to know what's going on?
我被告了  就是这事
I'm being sued. That's what's going on.
-被布莱恩吗  -不是  被斯蒂芬妮
- By Brian? - No, by Stephanie.
告你性骚扰  路易  这可不妙啊
For sexual harassment? Louis, this is bad.
我知道  瑞秋
I know what it is, Rachel.
那我们得谈谈你准备如何应对
Well, then we need to talk about how you're gonna handle it.
不  我们得谈谈你准备如何应对
No, we need to talk about how you're gonna handle it.
路易  这不是个好主意
Louis, that's not a good idea.
这是唯一的好主意
It's the only good idea.
你得马上过去那边  了结此事
You need to go over there right now and put an end to this.
-我不能这么做  -为什么
- I can't do that. - Why not?
因为继你之后我也和斯蒂芬妮起了冲突
Because I had a run-in with Stephanie after you did,
在唐娜炒了她之后又起了一次冲突
and then I had another run-in with her after Donna fired her.
她绝不会听我的
She's not gonna listen to me.
这可是性骚扰啊  瑞秋
It is sexual harassment, Rachel.
我的记录里不能有这种污点
I cannot have it on my record.
必须有人去劝服她  让她撤诉
Someone needs to convince her to let this go,
这人必须得是一个我信任的律师
and it needs to be a lawyer I can trust,
同时还必须是一个和她水平相近的人
but it also needs to be someone who's close to her level,
不然她就会觉得自己被攻击了
or she's gonna feel attacked.
那我有个绝佳人选
Then I think I have the perfect choice.
卡特里娜
Katrina.
看来路易收到我的起诉了
I take it Louis got my lawsuit.
没错  我来问你怎么现在提起诉讼
He did, and I'm here to ask why you're bringing it now.
因为你对他的言论指控...
Because the things you're alleging he said--
对他的言论指控
Alleging he said?
看来你不是以朋友  而是律师身份来的
I guess it's lawyer first, friend second.
不是这样  正因为我们是朋友我才来
That's not fair. I'm only here because we're friends.
也因为你想让我忘了皮尔逊-斯佩克特-
And because you wanted to convince me to forget
利特律所毁了我的事业
that Pearson Specter Litt ruined my career.
斯特芬尼  我知道你被解雇了
Stephanie, I know you got fired,
但是这场诉讼会毁了路易
but this lawsuit could destroy Louis.
我整理一下
Let me get this straight.
那个曾让我为了个对我刻薄
The woman who convinced me to leave a good job
性骚扰  并将我解雇的公司
for one where I was treated terribly,
而放弃了份好工作的女人
sexually harassed, and then fired
现在想找我帮忙
is now asking me for a personal favor?
是的  没错
Yes, I am.
我现在没心情帮别人忙
Well, I'm not in the mood to grant one.
所以你可以告诉路易我们法庭上见
So you can tell Louis I will see him in court.
斯特芬尼  我在兰德-考德-赞恩律所
Stephanie, the woman I knew
认识的那个女人可不是这样的
at Rand Kaldor Zane wouldn't do this.
拜托...
Please...
告诉我实情我才能帮你
tell me what's going on so I can help.
我在这儿听到些闲话
I heard people here talking,
他们说我被解雇是因为我工作不利
and they said that I got fired because I couldn't hack it.
这不是真的
Well, that's not true,
我也不能让他们有这种想法
and I won't have them thinking it is.
那就关上门来坐好
Then close that door and sit down,
因为我保证我们
because I'm betting that we can work out a deal
能想出对策
right now that shows anyone
让那些小看你的人知道你有多厉害
who's ever underestimated you just how strong you are.
亚历克斯  你见唐娜了吗
Alex, have you seen Donna by any chance?
-什么  -唐娜  你见她了吗
- What? - Donna. Have you seen her?
-我有话跟她说  -没见过  哈维
- I need to tell her something. - I don't know, Harvey.
我没时间关注你前秘书的
I don't have time to track your former secretary's
一举一动
every damn move.
你怎么回事
What the hell's wrong with you?
我告诉你我怎么回事
I'll tell you what's wrong with me.
马斯特森建筑公司对这件监狱案件很恼火
Masterson Construction's pissed about this prison case.
还没消火  你都按他们的要求做了啊
Still? You handed it off like they asked.
不  他们想让案子了结  不是被移交
No, they wanted the thing gone, not handed off,
现在这已经变成集体诉讼案了
and now it's turned into a class action,
明天就要开庭了
and it's going to trial tomorrow.
听我说  你的工作并不是了结此案
Listen to me, it's not your job to make this thing go away.
哈维  我是他们的律师  他们有麻烦
Harvey, I'm their attorney. They had a problem,
他们想把它解决掉  而我没做好
they wanted it fixed, and I didn't fix it.
胡扯  你让皮尔逊-斯佩克特把它当
Bullshit, you got Pearson Specter to drop it
烫手山芋一样扔了  你也只能做到这步了
like a hot potato. That's all you could've done.
不  我本该把整个案子都处理掉
No, what I could have done was kill the whole damn thing.
因为我没做好  他们在其它监狱找了个犯人
And since I didn't, they found some inmate at another prison
把这个案子闹大了
to break the case wide open,
我也为此吃了许多苦头
which is why I just had to eat a ton of shit.
你刚刚说什么
What did you just say?
我说他们在其它监狱找到个证人
I said they found a witness at another prison,
而我现在快把客户丢了
and now I'm gonna lost my goddamn client.
你要去哪儿
Where you going?
我说了  我找唐娜有事
Like I said, I need to find Donna.
立刻回答我  你知道迈克在哪儿吗
I want to know right now, do you know where Mike is?
-不  我不知道  -你不知道他在哪儿
- No, I don't. - You don't know where,
还是不知道他在办哪个案子
or you don't know what case he's working on?
我都不知道  但如果你冷静点
I don't know either one, but if you calm down,
或许我能帮你找到他
then maybe I can help you find him.
不  瑞秋  我不想让你帮我找他
No, Rachel, I don't want help finding him
事实上  我不想让你告诉他
In fact, I don't want you telling him
我有找过他
I was looking for him at all.
-奥斯卡・雷耶斯  -什么事
- Oscar Reyes? - Yes.
我是哈维・斯佩克特  我注意到
My name is Harvey Specter. It's come to my attention
你正在提起一桩集体诉讼案
that you're filing a class-action lawsuit.
没错  你有什么事
We are. How can I help you?
无偿法律服务对我们律所意义重大
Our pro bono work means a lot to us.
我们对待案子也非常认真
We take it very seriously,
我现在有个难以启齿的问题想问你
and I have a very difficult question to ask you.
-什么  -我想知道
- What is it? - I need to know
你对本案的处理方式是否满意
if you're happy with the way your case is being handled,
因为如果迈克・罗斯没有尽心尽力的...
because if Mike Ross isn't doing everything he can
-帮你  -打住
- to help you-- - Stop right there.
罗斯先生可是全心投入
Mr. Ross has dedicated himself
为我儿子讨回公道
to finding justice for my son.
不仅如此  当我提出和解时
And not only that, when I was offered a settlement,
他说服我不要和解而是寻求真相
he convinced me to turn it down and find out the real truth,
所以你告诉管事的  本案别让其他人插手
so you tell whoever's in charge that I don't want anyone else
我只相信迈克和奥利佛
working on this case other than Mike and Oliver.
谢谢
Thank you.
你向我保证过
You gave me your word
你不会插手那个监狱案
you'd stay the hell out of that prison case.
-哈维  我...  -你要站在我面前
- Harvey, I-- - You're gonna stand there
跟我说你没插手此案吗
and tell me you're not working on it?
因为奥斯卡・雷耶斯告诉我你为他做的事
Because Oscar Reyes told me you deserve a medal
都该拿块奖牌了
for what you're doing for him.
哈维  我确实是想让法律诊所接手的
Harvey, I meant to let the clinic handle it, okay?
后来发现这案子比我们想的要严重
It just turned out that this thing was bigger than we thought.
它就是变成
I don't give a shit
一场世纪审判我都不在乎
if it turned into the trial of the century.
我们有言在前
We had an agreement.
不  是你和亚历克斯的协议
No, you had an agreement with Alex,
我同意在文件上签字
and then I agreed to sign a document,
但事实证明  反腐对我来说
but as it turns out, stopping corruption
要比客户底线重要的多
is more important to me than some client's bottom line.
清醒清醒吧  现在就停下来
Then grow the hell up, because that ends now.
哈维  我得坚持到底
Harvey, I have to see this through.
坚持到底  你疯了吗
See this through? Are you out of your mind?
你以为我不知道加洛在帮你办这个案子吗
You think I don't know this is what Gallo was helping you with?
我告诉过你  加洛不成问题
I told you, Gallo is not gonna be a problem.
我跟你说过像加洛这种人总会成为麻烦
And I told you guys like Gallo are always a problem.
好吧  我跟你说过
Yeah, and what about what I told you happens
如果我对他违背誓言会发生什么
if I go back on my word with him now?
或者像你说的他给瑞秋打电话又会怎样
Or what you said about what happens if he calls Rachel.
你说你付钱他就帮你
Were you lying when you said you'd pay him
-是骗我的吗  -不  不是
- if he came through for you? - No, I wasn't.
现在打钱给他
Then pay him right now.
我替你付  但你不能再插手此案
You can take it out of my pocket, but you're done.
-哈维  不是...  -不  是你听我说
- Harvey, it's not-- - No, listen to me
因为我不希望你对我的话还有不清楚
because I don't want there to be any misunderstanding.
除了告诉奥利佛这案子归他管以外
You spend one more minute on this case,
不要在这案子上再花一分钟时间
other than telling Oliver it's his,
-就这么定了  -你什么意思
- I'm shutting you down. - What the hell does that mean?
意思是说明天我要出席听证会
It means I'm going to the hearing tomorrow
当场告发你违背协议
and telling them that you broke your agreement.
不管负责聆讯的法官是谁
And I don't care who the judge is,
那家律所都一定会被踢出这起案子
they'll toss the clinic off the case,
而你的朋友奥斯卡也一个子儿都拿不到
and your friend Oscar won't get a dime.
路易  别搅了  我有消息告诉你
Louis, stop blending! I have news.
卡特里娜  谢天谢地你终于回来了
Katrina, thank God you're back.
来  喝一杯李子泥
Here, have a prunie.
你到底弄了多少李子泥
Exactly how many prunies did you make?
不知道  我是借此发泄压力
I don't know. I'm stress blending.
如果待会儿你说的不是好消息
If I don't hear some good news soon,
世界将会出现李子短缺危机
there's gonna be an international prune shortage.
所以请一定要告诉我
So please tell me that you talked Stephanie
你成功说服斯蒂芬妮撤诉
out of this bullshit.
路易  我没能说服她
Louis, I couldn't talk her out of it,
但我说服她接受了这个交易
but I did manage to talk her into this.
好吧  这种程度我还能接受
Okay, well, I can live with this amount.
但这里写着我承认对她进行过性骚扰
But this says that I admit to sexually harassing her.
-事实如此  -一派胡言
- You did sexually harass her. - Oh, that's a load of crap.
我从没有调戏过斯蒂芬妮・帕特尔
I never hit on Stephanie Patel.
据法律定义性骚扰不单指调戏  你知道的
And that's not the definition of harassment, and you know it.
我不管  我不接受
Well, I don't care. I can't accept it.
为什么
Why not?
因为我以前也被控告过性骚扰
Because I've been sued for sexual harassment before,
我不能把自己弄得像个惯犯
and I can't have it look like a pattern.
我并不知情
I didn't know.
那是你来这里之前的事了  那起诉讼
It was before your time, and it was a bullshit suit
纯粹是丹尼尔・哈德曼一手捏造的
concocted by Daniel Hardman.
我不能被打上惯犯的烙印
I can't have a reputation for this.
我明白  路易  但斯蒂芬妮担心
I understand that, Louis, but Stephanie is worried
给别人留下办事不力的印象
people think she can't hack it as a lawyer,
而逼迫你承认过错则是她认为
and making you admit to what you did
可以扭转旁人看法的唯一方式
is the only way she sees to make them think otherwise.
抱歉  我不能签字
- I'm sorry. I can't sign it.
路易  我知道这不是你想要的结果
Louis, I know this isn't what you wanted,
但就我的专业意见
but in my professional opinion,
这是你最好的选择
this is the best you're going to do.
至少用一天时间  好好考虑
At least take a day to think about it.
路易  自不待言
And, Louis, this goes without saying,
无论你多想见斯蒂芬妮  都不要去
but however tempted you are, don't go see Stephanie.
你好
Hey.
我不好
Don't "Hey" me.
看来你听说我和哈维之间的事了
I take it you heard about what happened between me and Harvey.
看来你是没听说
I take it you didn't hear
我和哈维之间发生的事
about what happened between me and Harvey.
瑞秋  他跟你说什么了
Rachel, what did he tell you?
他没跟我说什么
He didn't tell me anything.
只是问我你在哪里以及你在忙什么
He asked me where you were and what you were working on,
我不得不当面对他撒谎
and I had to lie to his face.
-瑞秋  我...  -你听见我说的话了吗
- Rachel, I-- - Did you hear me?
我不得不当面对他撒谎
I had to lie to Harvey's face.
是的  我听见了  对不起
Yes, I heard you, and I'm sorry.
我不想听对不起
I don't want to hear "I'm sorry."
你想听的是你会就此罢手
I want to hear that you're dropping this goddamn thing.
-瑞秋  我...  -不要找借口
- Rachel, I-- - No excuses.
你说过这是你对奥斯卡・雷耶斯的承诺
You said it's your word to Oscar Reyes
这对你很重要
that mattered to you.
你知道吗  迈克
Well, you know what, Mike?
你需要把你做事的优先次序搞清楚
You need to get your priorities straight,
是因为你  现在我也没有了信誉
because my word became nothing today,
而且我不想再因为你陷入这种境地
and I don't ever want to be put in that position again.
决定权在你  你要么去法律诊所工作
So it's up to you. You either go and work at the clinic
要么继续留在皮尔逊・斯佩克特
or you stay at Pearson Specter,
但你不能再像现在这样把两边都当傻瓜
but what you can't do anymore is play them both for fools
还让我来当你的挡箭牌
and put me in the middle.
我要走了  等我回来
I'm gonna go now, and when I come back,
告诉我你的决定
you can let me know what you've decided.
这么巧
Oh, hey, you.
宝拉  你怎么来了
Paula, what are you doing here?
我刚好在附近
I was in the neighborhood,
想着也许我们能共进晚餐
and I was thinking maybe we could get dinner.
对不起
Listen, I'm sorry,
我今晚没心情
but I am just not in the mood tonight.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
这和你对唐娜说起
Does this have something to do with
我们的事情有关吗
how it went when you told Donna about us?
什么  不是
What? No.
我都还没找到机会告诉她
I didn't even get a chance to tell her.
没有找到机会是什么意思
Well, what does that mean, you didn't get the chance?
我本来打算说  但临时出了点事
It means I went to tell her, but something came up.
什么事
What exactly came up?
是什么事情重要吗
What does it matter what came up?
我只是好奇到底是什么事能重要到
Well, I'm just wondering what was so important
让你一整天都抽不出一点时间去告诉她
that you couldn't find the time to tell her the entire day.
好吧  如果你真的想知道
Well, if you really need to know,
一个杀人犯正和迈克合作办案
a murderer turns out to be working with Mike
而这案子是他向我发过誓不会再碰的
on a case he swore to me he wouldn't be working on.
我一整天都在想办法解决这个问题
I spent the entire day trying to fix it.
我觉得比起告诉唐娜
And I thought it was more important
我的感情生活  这事更重要
than telling Donna about my love life.
抱歉  我就不该问
I'm sorry I asked.
我没想反应这么大
Look, I didn't mean to overreact.
只是今天我过得太糟了
I've just had a hell of a day,
我保证明天就跟她说
and I'll tell her tomorrow, I promise.
哈维  你无需保证我任何事
Harvey, you don't need to promise me anything.
其实如果你不介意
In fact, I'd like to stay out of it entirely,
我宁愿抽身事外
if you don't mind.
-宝拉...  -真的没关系
- Paula-- - No, it's fine.
因为  这事本来都不是我提起的
Because, you know, I'm not the one that brought it up.
老实说  我不喜欢看到你表现得
And, frankly, I don't like you behaving as though
似乎是我逼你这么做的
I'm the one making you do this.
你到底怎么了
What's going on here?
因为你更倾向于
What's going on here is you're rather keen
把我们的恋情向唐娜保密
on keeping our relationship a secret from Donna...
而你却能毫无顾忌地向路易坦白
when you clearly had no trouble telling Louis.
你是在担心我对唐娜有感觉吗
Are you worried that I have feelings for her?
你当然对她有感觉
Of course you have feelings for her.
在她离开你以后你就开始恐慌发作了
You started having panic attacks after she left you.
要不是因为你的恐慌发作
We wouldn't even know each other
我们甚至都不会相识
if it weren't for those feelings.
-你到底想说什么  -我不知道
- Then what are you saying? - I don't know.
也许你并不想告诉她
Maybe you don't want to tell her
是因为你喜欢当她的焦点和倾慕对象
because you like being the object of her attention and affection,
你担心坦白之后就会改变现状
and you're worried this will change that.
她的焦点和倾慕对象
Her attention and affection?
你非要我说出来吗  哈维
Would you like me to say it, Harvey?
她爱你
She loves you.
至少她内心某处爱着你
At least part of her does,
也许你内心某处也喜欢且不想失去这种感觉
and maybe part of you likes it and doesn't want it to stop.
如果你有勇气告诉唐娜
And we wouldn't even be discussing this
让她朝前看
if you had the courage to tell Donna the truth
我们就不用讨论这个了
and let her move on.
对于一个
You know, for someone
不想再掺和这件事的人来说
who didn't want to be involved in this anymore,
你可真是话很多
you sure have a hell of a lot to say.
那我再说一件事
Then I'll say one more thing.
如果我说的不对  那你早上
If what I'm saying is wrong, then you won't have any trouble
把我们俩的事告诉唐娜就不会那么困难
telling Donna in the morning.
迈克  你去哪了
Mike, where the hell have you been?
撤案动议就在明天
The motion to dismiss is tomorrow.
我得整个过一遍
I need to go over everything--
奥利佛  我不能再帮你了
Oliver, I can't help you anymore.
什么
What?
我说我不能再跟这个案子了
I said I can't work the case anymore.
为什么不能
Why the hell not?
因为哈维知道了
'Cause Harvey found out.
该死  你...
Shit, are you--
他不会告发我们  但是他的态度很明确
He's not gonna hand us in, but he did make it clear
如果我再在这个案子上花一秒
that if I spent another second on this case
他就会毁掉整件事
that he'll pull the plug on the whole damn thing.
真是难以置信  在我们上庭的前一晚
I don't believe this. I mean, you come here
你把这颗炸弹扔到我面前
and you drop this bomb on me the night before we go to court.
奥利佛  不是炸弹  你一直都知道的
Oliver, it's not a bomb. You knew all along
你得独立完成
you were gonna have to do this on your own.
我知道你不会在我身边
I knew you wouldn't be up there next to me,
但我还指望这你帮我做准备
but I was counting on you helping me to prepare.
-奥利佛  -该死  迈克
- Oliver-- - Son of a bitch, Mike!
你知道我身上发生过什么
You know what happens to me!
上次就发生了  明天也会发生的
It happened last time, and now it's gonna happen tomorrow
因为你把我晾一边了
because you're goddamn hanging me out to dry!
你知道吗  奥利佛  我受够了
You know what, Oliver? I have had it up to here
你每做一个选择都要怪我
with you blaming me for every choice that you make.
当你同意接下这个案子的时候
You knew there would come a time when you'd be up there
你就知道总有一天你得独自站在那
by yourself when you agreed to take this case.
上次我们面临这样的情况的时候
Now, last time we were in this situation,
我照顾了你一夜  你还是搞砸了
I coddled you all night, and you still dropped the goddamn ball.
所以这次我们的准备方式就是我告诉你
So, this time, we're gonna prepare by me telling you
不要在像个小孩子一样了
to stop acting like a little boy,
要开始像个男人一样  把事情搞定
start acting like a man, and get the goddamn job done!
因为如果你做不到的话  奥斯卡还有那些囚犯
Because if you don't, Oscar and those prisoners,
他们就什么都没有了
they're gonna be left with nothing.
谢谢
Thank you.
斯特芬妮
Stephanie.
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
我一直在想你的条件
I've been thinking about your offer,
我希望我们能谈谈
and I was hoping we could talk.
我们不能  因为我们是原告和被告
Well, we can't because we're on opposite sides of a lawsuit.
我知道
I know that,
你想让我签什么协议我都愿意签
and I'm willing to sign whatever you want.
你想让我赔多少钱我都愿意赔
I'm willing to pay whatever you want.
我只是不能承认我...
I just can't admit that I--
做过的事
Did exactly what you did.
太糟了
Too bad.
因为你不愿意承认
Because if you won't admit it,
我会让陪审团来帮你承认
I'll make a jury admit it for you.
斯特芬妮  我是想来讲道理的
Stephanie, I'm trying to be reasonable here.
也许在你将自己置于
Well, maybe you should have thought of that
被低级的律师打败的境地之前
before putting yourself in a position
你就应该想到了
to let a lowly associate wipe the floor with you.
打败...  我的名声
Wipe the--My reputation is that of a pillar
在法律界是数一数二的
of the legal community,
所以你不要做梦能打败我了
so you're not wiping the floor with shit.
你的名声就是你是个混蛋
Your reputation is that you're a son of a bitch,
而我会向全世界证明这一点
and I'm gonna prove it to the world.
不  斯特芬妮  你唯一能证明的
No, Stephanie, the only thing you're gonna prove is that
就是你正如别人认为的一样  是个可悲的失败者
you're the pathetic loser that everyone thinks you are,
因为你挑起了一场
because you just picked a fight
对手远超你的水平的战争
with someone who is way out of your league!
你活在什么样的幻想世界里啊
What delusional reality are you living in?
一个我会在庭审上说得清清楚楚
The one where I make it crystal clear at trial
你因为被解雇
that you were fired for cause
而策划了这场诉讼来泄愤
and concocted this lawsuit out of spite.
我没有虚构满满一屋子
I didn't concoct a room full of witnesses
看到和听到真正的路易・利特的证人
who saw and heard the real Louis Litt.
所以在我看来  你将欠我很多很多钱
So the way I see it, you're gonna owe me so much money,
多到我再也不用去工作了
I'm never gonna need another job again.
哈维  你在这干什么
Harvey, what are you doing here?
执行合伙人不能偶尔
Can't a managing partner have a drink
和他最喜欢的首席运营官喝一杯吗
with his favorite COO every once in a while?
能  但是我有一大堆的工作要做
He can, but I got a ton of work to do,
我还想在午夜之前回家
and I'd like to get home before midnight.
我有事要告诉你
There's something I need to tell you.
哈维  怎么了
Harvey, what's going on?
我一直在见宝拉・阿加德
I've been seeing Paula Agard.
不再是见心理医生那种
And not as my therapist anymore.
我们在交往
We've been seeing each other.
-怎么  -什么怎么
- What? - What do you mean what?
我只是觉得你以为我不知道很好笑
I'm just amused that you think I didn't know.
-唐娜  -在你当上执行合伙人那天
- Donna. - The day you made managing partner,
你自己开车来上班  不是开的红色的车
you drove yourself to work, not in the red car,
而是开的黑色法拉利代托纳
but in the black Ferrari Daytona.
最重要的是  你告诉我和路易
And on top of that, you told me and Louis
那天晚上你有事要处理
that you had things to take care of that night,
但我知道你的日程
but I know your schedule,
我知道你自己直接从公司
and I know what happened was you drove yourself
开车回家  换上了你觉得
straight home from the office, you changed into whatever outfit
最能打动她的衣服
you thought would impress her the most,
然后直奔她家
and then you went right over to her house,
把她迷得神魂颠倒
and you swept her off her feet.
但是你那天晚上还问我怎么了
But you just asked me the other night if something was going on
因为我的举止不同以往
because I've been acting different.
那是因为我努力让你敞开心扉
'Cause I was trying to get you to open up,
但是你没有理解到
but you missed the signal,
所以我想我就等着好了  你这不就来了
so I figured I'd just keep on waiting, and here you are,
时间差不多
more or less right on time.
-差不多  -我给你的期限是明天
- More or less? - Well, I was giving you until tomorrow,
所以实际上你提前完成了
so you're actually ahead of schedule.
那是宝拉的贡献
Well, that was Paula's doing.
-我很为你高兴  哈维  我想听你从头说起
- I'm happy for you, Harvey, and I want to hear all about it,
但是如我所说  我有一大堆事要做
but like I said, I've got a ton of work to do,
我还想在午夜前回家  所以...
and I want to get home before midnight, so...
继续  工作吧  以后聊
Go on, finish. We'll talk later.
我很开心你终于告诉我了
I'm glad you finally told me.
谢谢  唐娜  我也是
Thanks, Donna. Me too.
唐娜  你还好吗
Donna, are you okay?
你看起来就和见鬼了一样
You look like you just saw a ghost.
我不知道  我...
I don't know. I...
我刚收到了一些我早该料到
I just got some news I should have seen coming,
却没能料到的消息
and I didn't.
你想谈谈吗
Do you want to talk about it?
不  不用  我没事的
No, I don't. I'll--I'll be fine.
我刚也收到了消息
Well, I just got some news
是我们应该但没能料到的
that we should have seen coming but didn't,
而且还不是好消息
and it's not good.
是什么
What is it?
我们收到了传票要去指证路易
We've just been subpoenaed to testify against Louis.
那是什么
What's that?
木须肉和炒饭
Moo shu pork and fried rice.
我之前那么跟你说话
The way I treated you before,
所以不确定你吃了没
I wasn't sure if you'd eaten yet.
-哈维  -然后我觉得我们可以边吃
- Harvey-- - And I was thinking that maybe we could eat
边告诉你  我很抱歉
while I tell you that I'm sorry
以及  我跟唐娜说了
and that I told Donna.
-你跟她说了  -是的  你是对的
- You told her? - Yes. You were right.
我得告诉她  不然这对她不公平
I needed to tell her, and it was unfair to her,
对你也不公平
and it was unfair to you.
-我可没那么说过  -没有  但你有这个意思
- I never said that. - No, but you meant it.
哈维  你一个不小心
Harvey, if you're not careful,
就要变成一个成熟且优秀的男友了
you're gonna become a full-fledged outstanding boyfriend.
男友
Boyfriend?
Boyfriend.
那我就尽量不小心一点
Then I'll try not to be careful.
进来吧
Come in.
对了  她听过之后有什么反应吗
By the way, how did she take it?
她没事的
She was fine.
-你确定吗  -确定
- Are you sure? - Yeah.
她好像早就知道了
Turned out she already knew.
我很高兴你告诉她了
Well, I'm glad you told her.
我还希望你买的东西里有蛋卷
And I hope you got some egg rolls in there.
卡特里娜
Katrina, hey.
路易  你干了什么
Louis, what the hell did you do?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
那为什么昨晚唐娜和瑞秋
Then why were Donna and Rachel
甩给我一张传票
slapped with subpoenas last night?
卡特里娜  听我说
Katrina, listen to me--
该死的  路易
God damn it, Louis!
在我明确告诉过你不要那么做之后
How long did you wait to go over there
你忍了多久就忍不住了
after I explicitly told you not to?
而且  这已经不重要了
Well, you know what? It doesn't matter,
因为你现在的工作是要击垮那个女人
because now your job is to blow that woman out of the water.
那是相当有难度的
Well, that's gonna be pretty hard,
因为她有一帮证人
since she has a room full of witnesses
还有唐娜的录音  说你做错了
and she also has Donna on record saying what you did was wrong
以及这就是为什么你失去了对助理律师的领导
and that's why you lost dominion over the associates.
唐娜干了什么
Whoa, Donna did what?
她也不知道你会被起诉  路易
She didn't know you were going to get sued, Louis.
斯特芬妮让她出庭作证  我们就完了
And when Stephanie gets her up on the stand, we're dead.
那她就只能出庭做伪证了
Well, then she's just gonna have to lie on the stand.
路易  这根本就是疯了  你也知道
- Louis, that is insane, and you know it.
该死的  我们总要想个方法啊
Well, God damn it, we have to figure some way to get out of this,
因为我今年已经失去了一切
because I have lost everything this year
我不能再失去这个了
and I can't lose this.
那不如你去向她道歉吧
How about you tell her you're sorry?
你说什么
What the hell did you just say?
我说去向她道歉
I said tell her that you're sorry.
你来这儿干嘛  你是在替她监视我们吗
What are you even doing here? Are you spying on us for her?
没有  我是来告诉你我收到传票了
No, um, I came to tell you I'd been served with a subpoena.
好的  布莱恩  我不用你帮忙
Well, Brian, I don't need your help,
因为道歉就意味着要认罪
because you can't apologize without admitting guilt,
而这是我最不想做的事
which is the whole thing that I don't want to do.
路易  我不知道你有没有注意到
Louis, I don't know if you've noticed,
但不管怎么样这是少不了的
but that's pretty much going to happen anyway.
请允许我...
If I may...
这是认罪  但也是冒险试一把
it is admitting guilt, and it is taking a chance,
但如果是我因为你对我说的那些伤人的话
but if I were thinking of suing you
而起诉的你
for the horrible things you said to me...
那么这才是我想听到的
that's what I'd want to hear.
你在这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
我以为你不会再和这件事
I thought you weren't supposed to have
有任何瓜葛了
anything to do with this anymore.
是没有  但协议里也没说
I'm not, but there's nothing in that agreement
我不能来看我的朋友奥利弗
that says I can't come watch my friend Oliver
在庭上大展身手啊
kick some ass in court.
那赶快系好安全带
Well, strap the hell in.
因为这位帅哥要大展身手了
'Cause this motherfu--er is going down.
我可以进来吗
May I come in?
你这次又想要什么
What do you want this time?
告诉我我一文不值连办公室都不配有吗
Tell me I'm so worthless I don't even deserve an office?
我想来跟你道歉
I want to tell you I'm sorry,
要说一文不值的人  那也是我
and if anyone's worthless, it's me.
路易  如果你觉得假装给我道个歉
Louis, if you think pretending to give me an apology
就能让我撤诉的话
is gonna make me drop this suit,
你还会有别的麻烦的
you have another thing coming.
我不是这样想的
I don't think that.
我只是觉得自己欠你一个解释
I just think that I owe you an explanation.
你看...
You see...
在我对你说出那些话的
the night before
前一晚
I said those horrible things to you,
我的未婚妻离开了我
my fiancée left me.
她怀孕了
She was pregnant.
哪怕孩子不是我的
And even though the child wasn't mine...
我终于要当爸爸了
I was finally gonna be a dad.
而当一切消失的时候
And when all that went away,
我的整个人生都乱了
my entire life turned upside down.
我心烦意乱
I mean, I was reeling.
所以当时布莱恩来向我请假
So, when Brian had asked me for time off
说要去陪他老婆生孩子
to go have a baby
而你又替他说话
and you defended him...
你就把所有的火都发到了我身上
You took everything you were feeling out on me.
是的  我为此感到羞愧
Yeah, and I am ashamed of that.
斯特芬尼
Stephanie...
你想让我签什么文件都可以
I will sign anything you want.
只要能让大家都知道你不是个弱者
I will say anything you need to make sure
让我说什么都可以
that the world knows that you are not a pushover,
哪怕是认罪
even if that includes admitting guilt.
如果因为某种原因他们这里还是不要你
And if for some reason they still can't accept you here,
你就回来和我们一起  这是持续邀约
you have your job back with us, standing offer.
我很感谢你能对我敞开心扉  路易
I appreciate you opening up to me, Louis.
但这不是说大家觉得我是个弱者
But this wasn't really about people thinking I'm a pushover.
而是当你对我说出那些话时
It was about how you made me feel
你给我的感觉
when you said those things to me.
它们为什么会让你有感觉呢
Why would they make you feel anything?
那些话明显不是真的啊
I mean, they were so clearly untrue.
-是吗  -拜托
- Were they? - Come on.
你胡说什么呢  斯特芬妮
What are you talking about? Stephanie...
我34岁了  一周工作90小时
I'm 34 years old. I work 90 hours a week.
我没有任何亲人
I don't have anyone.
我没有时间约会
I don't have time to meet anyone,
我确实担心我永远也
and I'm worried that I never will,
永远也无法拥有一个家
that I--that I'll never have a family.
所以当你说没有人愿意和我要孩子时
So, when you said no one would want to have children with me...
我真的很抱歉  斯特芬妮
I am so sorry, Stephanie.
谢谢  路易
Thank you, Louis.
我真的很想过去抱你一下
I feel like I want to come over there and give you a hug,
但是恐怕不太合适
but it's probably inappropriate
因为你正在因为性骚扰起诉我
since you're suing me for sexual harassment.
我不打算告你了  路易
I'm not suing you anymore, Louis.
法官大人  本案完全是基于
Your Honor, this suit hinges on the testimony
一个罪犯的证词
of a convicted felon,
更别提整体原告都是
not to mention the entire class is made up of felons
找机会报复监狱的罪犯
looking for a chance to stick it to the prisons
只是监狱完成了监禁他们的使命
that did their duty by incarcerating them.
法官大人  本案并非基于
Your Honor, this case doesn't hinge
弗兰克・加洛的证词
on the word of Frank Gallo.
而是基于一位美国检察官的证词
It hinges on the word of a U.S. Attorney
而且该检察官曾有足够证据怀疑
who had reason to suspect abuses were taking place
这些所谓的正直监狱虐待犯人
at these supposedly upstanding prisons.
法官大人  那份文件不可采用
Your Honor, that file is inadmissible.
证据开示程序中我们没有见到
We weren't presented with it during discovery.
格雷迪先生  如果你这是故意...
Mr. Grady, if this is some sort of end-around--
法官大人  请您看看这份文件
Your Honor, if you'll look at the file,
你会看到我是昨天才收到的
you can see it was delivered to me yesterday.
所以除非辩方律师认为美国检察官
So, unless opposing counsel feels the U.S. Attorney
伪造了日期  那么这份文件就可以采用
was fabricating that date, that file is admissible.
斯特林小姐  除非你有其他原因
Ms. Sterling, unless you have another reason
支持本案不应继续进行
as to why this case shouldn't move forward,
否则我只能允许了
I'm inclined to allow it.
我有足够的理由  法官大人
I have a compelling reason, Your Honor.
-你是谁  -我叫亚历克斯・威廉姆斯
- And who are you? - My name is Alex Williams.
法官大人  此人无权参与本案
Your Honor, this man has no standing in this case.
我不同意  因为我有份具约束力协议
I beg to differ, because I have a binding agreement
由他们的法律诊所签署  表示他们
signing by his legal clinic stating they would have
在本案上绝不接受皮尔逊-斯佩克特-
no outside help from Pearson Specter Litt
-利特的帮助  他们违约了  -你没有证据
- on this case, yet they did. - You have no proof of that.
那不如你上证人席  宣誓作证
Then how about I put you on the stand, swear you in,
-我再来问你这问题  -没有理由
- and ask you myself? - There is no basis
也没有先例允许你这么做
for you doing that, there is no precedent for you doing that,
我也绝对不会被人胁迫作证
and I'm not gonna get bullied to getting up on the stand.
而且我要说清楚  法官大人  法庭
And for the record, Your Honor, the court cannot make
无权因为我拒绝作证对我产生偏见
any inferences based on me choosing not to go up there.
那不如我让迈克・罗斯出庭作证
Then how about I put Mike Ross on the stand?
我看到他就坐在那里
I notice he's sitting right over there.
我现在没有给他的传票
I don't have a subpoena for him,
但我相信申请一张并不难
but I'm sure we can whip one up.
等他上了证人席
And when he gets up there,
我们再看看他有没有说实话
we'll see if he tells the truth or not.
-法官大人  -够了
- Your Honor-- - That's enough.
法官大人  我是违反了协议
Your Honor, I violated the agreement.
那我没有选择  只能撤销本案
Then I have no other choice but to dismiss this case.
你没事吧
Hey. You okay?
我很好  怎么了
Yeah, I'm fine. Why?
显示昨天我进来时你的表情
First, the way you were when I walked in last night
现在我跟你说了传票的事你又成这样了
and then how you were after I told you about the subpoena.
我只是担心路易  瑞秋
Well, I was just worried about Louis, Rachel.
他被起诉了  我觉得我有责任
He's being sued, and I feel partially responsible
因为是我当着
because I'm the one who admitted
新律师的面承认他确实做错了
in front of the associates that he was wrong.
我认识你的这么长时间
And I've known you long enough to know
也足够我判断你什么时候在骗我了
when you're not being straight with me.
哈维昨晚跟我说他有了恋人
Harvey told me he's involved with somebody last night.
-认真的吗  -很认真
- Is it serious? - Yes.
这才是你没想到的会发生的那件事
And that's the news you should have seen coming.
-是的  -唐娜  你只是凡人
- Yes. - Donna, you're only human,
我知道你对人心的解读出神入化
and I know you have this amazing ability to read people,
但有时候有些事你也会忽略
but some things are gonna slip by even you once in a while.
我没有忽略这件事  瑞秋
This one didn't slip by, Rachel.
我没想到会发生  是因为我不想去想
I didn't see it coming 'cause I didn't want to see it.
我总说我希望哈维幸福  我也真的希望
I've always said that I want Harvey to be happy, and I do.
但这件事还是困扰着你
But it bothers you.
而且我讨厌这种感觉
And I hate that it does.
结果他告诉我的时候  我还假装已经知道了
And then when he told me, I pretended I already knew,
这件事更让我郁闷
and I hate that even more.
我不知道该说什么了
I don't know what to say.
我都不知道希望你对我说什么
I don't even know what I'd want you to say.
你说米歇尔・罗斯和哈利艾特・斯佩克特
What do you say Michelle Ross and Harriett Specter
这周再出去喝一次酒怎么样
go out for a drink this week?
谢谢  瑞秋  我很乐意
Thanks, Rachel. I'd like that.
你告诉他了是不是
You told him, didn't you?
你说什么呢  告诉谁什么了
What are you talking about? Told who what?
别糊弄我
Don't bullshit me.
你告诉亚历克斯我在办监狱案了
You told Alex I was working the prison case.
我什么也没告诉亚历克斯
I didn't tell Alex shit.
我只是让你放弃这个案子
What I did was I told you to drop it.
我也放弃了  我一眼都没有再看
And I did. I didn't spend one more second working on it,
完全遵从了你的命令
just like you ordered me to.
那你来找我闹什么
Then what the hell is your problem?
因为他刚刚出现在法庭
My problem is he just showed up to the courtroom
毁掉了整个案子
and blew up the case.
他羞辱了我们  羞辱了我
He embarrassed us, he embarrassed me,
当着庭上所有人的面
and he did it in front of everyone.
法庭  你不是说你不参与了吗
The courtroom? I thought you said you weren't involved.
我只是坐在后面
I was sitting in the back watching.
没有法律禁止  而且这不是重点
There's no law against that, and that is not the point.
不重点是你随便就判断
No, the point is you went from A to Z
是我告诉了他
and assumed that I told him.
不是你那他是怎么知道的
How the hell else would he know?
我怎么知道的跟你没关系
It's none of your damn business how I knew.
没你的事  这是我跟哈维的事
No, no, this is between me and Harvey.
错  这是我跟你之间的事
Wrong, this is between me and you
因为是你打破了和我委托人的协议
because you broke your agreement with my client.
我不管我干了什么
I don't care what I did.
你没有必要公开羞辱我们
You didn't have to do that publicly.
不是我想这么干  是你逼我的
I didn't make that decision. You did.
胡扯  你完全可以私下找我
Bullshit, you could have come to me privately.
我们可以谈谈这件事
We could've had a conversation.
这事一开始我就是这么做的
I did it when this thing started,
-我不打算再来一次  -混蛋
- and I'm not doing it again. - You son of a bitch.
他说的没错
He's right.
什么
What?
亚历克斯是对的  是你逼他的
Alex is right, you gave him no choice.
该死的  哈维  是监狱有问题
God damn it, Harvey, that prison is doing shady shit.
他的委托人不在乎是因为他们眼里只有钱
His client doesn't care because all they care about is money.
而且你签协议时就知道
And you knew that when you handed it off
-但你还是答应了  -这件事的重点是
- and said you'd live by it. - This is about you
-你去法庭...  -够了  事已至此
- coming into a courtroom and-- - Okay, that's it! It's done.
我永远不想再听到你们再提起
I don't want to hear another word about Reform Corp
兰伯特惩教所或者马斯特森建筑公司
or Masterson Construction ever again.
你做出了决定  就要承担后果
You made your bed. Now you're gonna sleep in it.
唐娜  你有时间吗
Donna, you have a minute?
路易  如果你是来为了我对
Louis, if you're here to berate me for what I said
斯特芬妮说的话指责我  那没时间
to Stephanie, then, no, I don't.
我不是为此而来
Uh, that is not why I'm here.
我来是想跟你说句对不起
I came to tell you that I'm sorry
我很抱歉几周前没有听你的话
that I didn't listen to you weeks ago.
你具体是指哪次没听我的话
You're gonna have to be a little more specific.
你一直跟我说我应该直面塔拉的事
You kept telling me that I wasn't dealing with Tara.
我终于走出了这一步  而且我想正是因此
Well, I finally started, and I think because of that,
我才终于能够放下愤怒
it allowed me to get past my anger
和斯特芬妮和解了
and make peace with Stephanie.
我很高兴你这么说  路易  我为你骄傲
I'm glad to hear it, Louis. I'm proud of you.
所以  真希望我早点听了你的话
Like I said, I wish I had listened to you sooner.
但正是你一点一点的打破了
But every bit of you hammering away
我否认的高墙我才最终推倒了它
at my wall of denial is what finally brought it down.
所以我是来跟你说谢谢的
So I'm here to tell you thank you...
因为现在我终于觉得
Because now I feel like I can finally
我能继续我的生活了
move forward with my life.
不客气  路易
You're welcome, Louis.
我想这意味着你终于准备好了
And I think that this means that you're officially ready.
-准备好什么  -重新接管新律师
- Uh, for what? - To take back the associates.
唐娜  不用  我很感激
Okay, Donna, no, I appreciate that.
-但他们是你的了  -他们从来都不是
- But they're yours now. - They were never mine, Louis.
我一直都只是在替你照顾他们
I was always just taking care of them for you.
我真不知道该如何报答你
I don't know how I can repay you.
你已经报答我了
You just did.
路易  如果你是来要史蒂文森的简报
Louis, if you're here for the Stevenson brief,
我明天一早就能交给你
I can have it to you in the morning.
回家吧  布莱恩
Go home, Brian.
我被解雇了吗
Am I fired?
不  只是工作并非生活的全部
Nope, there's just more to life than working here.
这是恶作剧吗
Am I being punked?
完全不是
No, not at all.
只是从明天开始你就有新上司了
It's just that you have a new supervisor starting tomorrow,
他希望你今晚能好好休息
and he would like you to get a good night's sleep.
然后他居然让你来通知我
And he told you to tell me that?
天哪  布莱恩  拜托  能配合点吗
Oh, Jesus, Brian, please, will you work with me?
我就是你的新上司
I'm the new supervisor.
听着  我很抱歉
And listen, I am sorry for saying
用那么恶劣的言辞说你不务正业
all those horrible things to you about undedicated.
我都无法想象你要怎么平衡初为人父
I can't even imagine how you balance being a new dad
和这里堆积如山的工作
with this workload.
那我们明天见了
Then I'll see you tomorrow.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
你走之前  我有东西给你
Before you go, I got you a little something.
只需要吐出来
路易  这是两个男人之间
Louis, this is the best onesie
赠送过的最好的一句话了
a man has ever gotten another man.
只要让那小家伙好好穿就好
You just tell the little guy to wear it well.
需要的话随时可以带孩子来上班
And feel free to bring him in whenever you want.
但是还是  先打个电话
But, you know, call first.
毕竟这里还是工作的地方
This is a place of business, for God's sake.
那是什么
What's that?
我早该还你的一样东西...
Something I should have given back to you a long time ago...
你的公寓钥匙
the key to your apartment.
什么意思
I don't understand.
我并非提前知道你和宝拉在一起了  哈维
I didn't know about you and Paula, Harvey,
而且我骗了你
and I kept it from you,
我不想继续瞒着你  因为我很为你开心
and I don't want to keep it from you because I'm happy for you.
-唐娜  -我说过我想要更多
- Donna-- - I said I wanted more,
我也已经得到了
and I got what I wanted.
但当你告诉我你们的事
But when you told me about the two of you,
-有那么一刻  我...  -我理解
- for a second there, I-- - I get it.
-真的吗  -我记得当我知道
- You do? - I remember how it felt
你和史蒂芬・亨特利的事时的感受
when I found out about you and Stephen Huntley.
我之前也告诉过你  我很困扰
And I told you before, it bothered me.
但那并不代表...
But it doesn't mean--
是的
Exactly.
我真的为你感到高兴  哈维
I really am happy for you, Harvey.
谢谢  唐娜
Thanks, Donna.
奥斯卡
Oscar.
是真的吗  今天发生在庭上的事
Is it true, what happened in court today?
-是的  但这只是个小挫折  -挫折
- Yes, but it's only a setback. - Setback?
他们说整个案子都被推翻了
They said they threw out the whole case.
不是推翻了案子  只是我们不能参与了
They didn't throw it out. They just threw us off of it.
这有什么区别
What the hell's the difference?
区别在于这是个有胜算的案子
The difference is it's a good case,
还可以由别人来起诉
and somebody else can still take it.
-我们只要  -别再哄我了
- We just have to-- - Stop bullshitting me!
是你劝我拒绝和解的
Now, you told me to turn down that settlement.
我相信了你  现在都完了
I trusted you, and now it's over.
还没有完  我知道
No, it's not over, and I know I told you
是我劝你拒绝和解  但你也说了
to turn down that settlement, but you told me
你起诉不是为了钱...
you weren't doing this for the money and--
我知道  我说了我为了伸张正义
Yes, I know. I told you I was doing it for justice.
但我也说了我还有一个儿子两个女儿
But I also told you I have a son and two other daughters,
你说愈合心伤的唯一办法
and you convinced me the only way to heal
就是避免让这种事发生在其他人身上
was to keep this from happening to someone else,
现在我一无所有了
and now I have nothing.
没钱  没伸张正义  也没有愈合
No money, no justice, no healing.
奥斯卡  我会弥补这件事的
Oscar, I'm gonna make it right.
等你做到我再相信你
I'll believe that when I see it!
哈维  如果你来是为了今天的事
Harvey, if this is about earlier today,
我很感激你支持了我
I want to thank you for backing me.
确实是关于今天的事  亚历克斯
It is about earlier today, Alex,
但我不是来让你感谢我的
but I'm not here for you to thank me.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
我认真想了迈克的话
I got to thinking about what Mike said,
他是对的
and he was right.
你本来可以安静解决此事  但你没有
You could've done what you did quietly, but you didn't.
哈维...
Harvey--
也就是说  你这样做并非只是为了
Which means this isn't just about you protecting
维护你委托人的利益
your client's interests.
而且是为了保护你自己
It's about you protecting yourself.
所以你还是把实话告诉我吧
So why don't you tell me what's really going on here?